Stephen Jay Gould Papers, 1899-2004
Stanford University Libraries.
- Series 3. Manuscripts
  - Subseries 1. Books
    - I Have Landed: The End of a Beginning in Natural History
      - I Have Landed, annotated galley, annotated typescript and correspondence, Tales of a Feathered Tail (Box 491, Folder 7)
      - I Have Landed, annotated typescript and correspondence, When Less is Truly More (Box 491, Folder 8)
      - I Have Landed, typescript and correspondence (Box 491, Folder 9)
      - I Have Landed, cover proof and notes (Box 509, Folder 5)
      - I Have Landed, annotated typescript, September 11,1901 (Box 521, Folder 1)
      - I Have Landed, correspondence and research (Box 521, Folder 2)
      - I Have Landed, reviews (Box 613, Folder 7)
      - I Have Landed, typescript, The Pre-Adamite in a Nutshell (Box 613, Folder 8)
      - I Have Landed, partial galley proof (Box 613, Folder 9)
      - I Have Landed, annotated typescript, Tales of a Feathered Tail (Box 613, Folder 10)
      - I Have Landed, annotated typescript, No Science Without Fancy, No Art Without Facts: The Lepidoptery of Vladimir Nabokov (Box 613, Folder 11)
    - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville: A Lifelong Passion for Baseball
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, early draft [Kay McCauley's Copy] (2 folders)
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, first pass galley proofs (2 folders)
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, first pass galley proofs, master set (2 folders), 2002 Nov 14
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, first pass galley proofs, grammar edits (2 folders)
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, first pass galley proofs, edits (2 folders)
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, second pass galley proofs (2 folders), 2002 Dec 3
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, second pass galley proofs, with edits (2 folders), 2002 Dec 3
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, original manuscript for proof reading (2 folders)
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, foreword, 3rd and 4th pass (Box 236, Folder 3)
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, editing, photo captions and photos (Box 236, Folder 4)
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, miscellaneous notes and clippings (Box 236, Folder 5)
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, typescript, A Time to Laugh (Box 267, Folder 5)
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, notes (Box 459, Folder 7)
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, annotated typescript, Sultan of Sentimentality (Box 459, Folder 8)
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, typescript, Table of Contents (Box 459, Folder 9)
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, annotated typescript, Fenway Crowns the Millennium (Box 483, Folder 13)
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, annotated typescript, Streetball From a New York City Boyhood (Box 483, Folder 14)
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, partial typescript and correspondence (Box 483, Folder 15)
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, annotated typescript and manuscript, Seventh Inning Stretch: Baseball, Father and Me Fragment of a Limited Autobiography (Box 481, Folder 13)
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, typescript, Late Innings (Box 512, Folder 10)
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, annotated typescript, The Amazing Dummy (Box 614, Folder 16)
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, typescript, I Love a Parade [ Tripping the Light Fantastic] (Box 614, Folder 17)
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, typescript, More Power to Him (Box 614, Folder 18)
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, annotated typescript, Rough Injustice (Box 614, Folder 19)
      - Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, reviews (Box 614, Folder 20)
    - The Hedgehog, the Fox, and the Magister's Pox: Mending the Gap Between Science and the Humanities
      - The Hedgehog, the Fox, and the Magister's Pox, research and notes (Folder 1)
      - The Hedgehog, the Fox, and the Magister's Pox, typescript, partial draft (2 folders) (Folder 2-3)
      - The Hedgehog, the Fox, and the Magister's Pox, typescript (2 folders)
      - The Hedgehog, the Fox, and the Magister's Pox, annotated typescript (2 folders)
      - The Hedgehog, the Fox, and the Magister's Pox, annotated typescript (3 folders)
      - The Hedgehog, the Fox, and the Magister's Pox, typescripts (7 folders)
      - The Hedgehog, the Fox, and the Magister's Pox, correspondence (Box 262, Folder 16)
      - The Hedgehog, the Fox, and the Magister's Pox, partial annotated typescript (Box 371, Folder 6)
      - The Hedgehog, the Fox, and the Magister's Pox, draft and annotated typescript (Box 509, Folder 1)
      - The Hedgehog, the Fox, and the Magister's Pox, annotated typescript, The Benefits of Pluribus (Box 509, Folder 2)
      - The Hedgehog, the Fox, and the Magister's Pox, partial annotated typescript (2 folders)
      - The Hedgehog, the Fox, and the Magister's Pox, original manuscript (2 folders)
  - Subseries 2. Natural History magazine column: This View of Life.
    - Natural History Magazine Column: This View of Life. Published Articles
      - Size & Shape, 1974 Jan (Box 384, Folder 1)
      - Sizing Up Human Intelligence, 1974 Feb (Box 384, Folder 2)
      - Race Problem, 1974 Mar (Box 217, Folder 1)
      - On Heroes and Fools in Science, 1974 Aug-Sep (Box 384, Folder 3)
      - The Great Dying, 1974 Oct (Box 384, Folder 4)
      - Darwin's Delay, and Evolution and the Brain, 1974 Dec-1975 Jan (Box 384, Folder 5)
      - Catastrophes and Steady State Earth, 1975 Feb (Box 217, 384, Folder 2, 6)
      - Velikovsky in Collision, 1975 Mar (Box 384, Folder 7)
      - Reverend Burnet's Dirty Little Planet, 1975 Apr (Box 217, 384, Folder 3, 8)
      - The Child as Man's Real Father, 1975 May (Box 384, Folder 9)
      - Racism and Recapitulation, 1975 Jun (Box 217, 384, Folder 10, 4)
      - Diversity Through Time, 1975 Oct (Box 384, Folder 11)
      - Posture Maketh the Man, 1975 Nov (Box 384, Folder 12)
      - A Threat to Darwinism, 1975 Dec (Box 384, Folder 13)
      - Darwin and the Captain, 1976 Jan (Box 384, Folder 14)
      - Human Babies as Embryos, 1976 Feb (Box 384, Folder 15)
      - Criminal Man Revived, 1976 Mar (Box 384, Folder 16)
      - Ladders, Bushes, and Human Evolution, 1976 Apr (Box 384, Folder 17)
      - Biological Potential vs. Biological Determinism, 1976 May (Box 384, Folder 18)
      - The Five Kingdoms, 1976 Jun (Box 384, Folder 19)
      - The Interpretation of Diagrams, 1976 Aug-Sep (Box 384, Folder 20)
      - Darwin's Untimely Burial, 1976 Oct (Box 384, Folder 21)
      - So Cleverly Kind an Animal, 1976 Nov (Box 384, Folder 22)
      - The Advantages of Eating Mom, 1976 Dec (Box 384, Folder 23)
      - The Problem of Perfection, 1977 Jan (Box 379, Folder 1)
      - The Continental Drift Affair, 1977 Feb (Box 379, Folder 2)
      - Twin-engined Spaceship Earth, 1977 Mar (Box 379, Folder 3)
      - The 120-year Bamboo Clock, 1977 Apr (Box 379, Folder 4)
      - Evolution's Erratic Pace, 1977 May (Box 379, Folder 5)
      - The Return of Hopeful Monsters, 1977 Jun-Jul (Box 379, Folder 6)
      - Our Allotted Lifetimes, 1977 Aug-Sep (Box 217, 379, Folder 5, 7)
      - Sticking Up for Marsupials, 1977 Oct (Box 379, Folder 8)
      - The Telltale Wishbone, 1977 Nov (Box 379, Folder 9)
      - Caring Groups and Selfish Genes, 1977 Dec (Box 379, Folder 10)
      - Nature's Odd Couples, 1978 Jan (Box 379, Folder 11)
      - An Early Start, 1978 Feb (Box 217, 379, Folder 12, 6)
      - Crazy Old Randolph Kirkpatrick, 1978 Mar (Box 379, Folder 13)
      - Bathybius Meets Eozoon, 1978 Apr (Box 380, Folder 1)
      - Were Dinosaurs Dumb?, 1978 May (Box 380, Folder 2)
      - Flaws In a Victorian Veil, 1978 Jun-Jul (Box 380, Folder 3)
      - The Great Scablands Debate, 1978 Aug-Sep (Box 380, Folder 4)
      - Women's Brains, 1978 Oct (Box 217, 380, Folder 5, 7)
      - The Panda's Peculiar Thumb, 1978 Nov (Box 380, Folder 6)
      - Senseless Signs of History, 1978 Dec (Box 380, Folder 7)
      - A Darwinian Paradox, 1979 Jan (Box 380, Folder 8)
      - Wide Hats and Narrow Minds, 1979 Feb (Box 380, Folder 9)
      - Piltdown Revisited, 1979 Mar (Box 380, Folder 10)
      - Time's Vastness, 1979 Apr (Box 380, Folder 11)
      - Mickey Mouse Meets Konrad Lorenz, 1979 May (Box 380, Folder 12)
      - Our Greatest Evolutionary Step, 1979 Jun-Jul (Box 380, Folder 13)
      - A Quahog is a Quahog, 1979 Aug-Sep (Box 380, Folder 14)
      - Shades of Lamarck, 1979 Oct (Box 380, Folder 15)
      - Perceptive Bees, Birds, and Bacteria, 1979 Nov (Box 217, 380, Folder 16, 8)
      - Darwin's Middle Road, 1979 Dec (Box 380, Folder 17)
      - Wallace's Fatal Flaw, 1980 Jan (Box 217, Folder 9)
      - In the Midst of Life, 1980 Feb (Box 381, Folder 1)
      - Death Before Birth, 1980 Mar (Box 381, Folder 2)
      - Dr. Down's Syndrome, 1980 Apr (Box 381, Folder 3)
      - The First Forebear, 1980 May (Box 381, Folder 4)
      - The Belt of an Asteroid, 1980 Jun (Box 217, 381, Folder 10, 5)
      - Hen's Teeth and Horse's Toes, 1980 Jul (Box 381, Folder 6)
      - The Piltdown Conspiracy, 1980 Aug (Box 381, Folder 7)
      - Vision with a Vengeance, 1980 Sep (Box 381, Folder 8)
      - Hopeful Monsters, 1980 Oct (Box 381, Folder 9)
      - Chance Riches, 1980 Nov (Box 381, Folder 10)
      - Science and Jewish Immigration, 1980 Dec (Box 381, Folder 11)
      - The Politics of Census, 1981 Jan (Box 217, Folder 11)
      - Hyena Myths and Realities, 1981 Feb (Box 217, Folder 12)
      - Kingdoms Without Wheels, 1981 Mar (Box 217, Folder 13)
      - A Most Chilling Statement, 1981 Apr (Box 217, Folder 14)
      - The Titular Bishop of Titiopolis, 1981 May (Box 217, Folder 15)
      - Piltdown in Letters, 1981 Jun (Box 217, Folder 16)
      - What, if Anything, Is a Zebra?, 1981 Jul (Box 217, Folder 17)
      - What Color is a Zebra?, 1981 Aug (Box 217, Folder 18)
      - Quaggas, Coiled Oysters, and Flimsy Facts, 1981 Sep (Box 217, Folder 19)
      - A Visit to Dayton, 1981 Oct (Box 217, Folder 20)
      - The Ultimate Parasite, 1981 Nov (Box 217, Folder 21)
      - Agassiz in the Galapagos, 1981 Dec (Box 217, Folder 22)
      - The Guano Ring, 1982 Jan (Box 217, Folder 23)
      - Nonmoral Nature, 1982 Feb (Box 217, Folder 24)
      - Moon, Mann, and Otto, 1982 Mar (Box 217, Folder 25)
      - The Importance of Trifles (Box 217, Folder 26)
      - Hutton's Purposeful View, 1982 May (Box 217, Folder 27)
      - The Stinkstones of Oeningen, 1982 Jun (Box 217, Folder 28)
      - The Oddball Human Male, 1982 Jul (Box 217, Folder 29)
      - Free to Be Extinct, 1982 Aug (Box 217, Folder 30)
      - Solitary Origins of Some Societies, 1982 Sep (Box 217, Folder 31)
      - The Hottentot Venus, 1982 Oct (Box 217, Folder 32)
      - Living with Connections, 1982 Nov (Box 217, Folder 33)
      - Of Wasps and WASPs, 1982 Dec (Box 217, Folder 34)
      - On Original Ideas, 1983 Jan (Box 217, Folder 35)
      - For Want of a Metaphor, 1983 Feb (Box 217, Folder 36)
      - Unconnected Truths, 1983 Mar (Box 217, Folder 37)
      - Opus 100, 1983 Apr (Box 217, Folder 38)
      - Mind and Supermind, 1983 May (Box 217, Folder 39)
      - A Life and Death Tail, 1983 Jun (Box 217, Folder 40)
      - Sex and Size, 1983 Aug (Box 217, Folder 41)
      - Darwin at Sea, 1983 Sep (Box 217, Folder 42)
      - False Premise, Good Science, 1983 Oct (Box 217, Folder 43)
      - Bound by the Great Chain, 1983 Nov (Box 217, Folder 44)
      - Chimp on the Chain, 1983 Dec (Box 217, Folder 45)
      - Just in the Middle, 1984 Jan (Box 217, Folder 46)
      - The Ediacaran Experiment, 1984 Feb (Box 217, Folder 47)
      - A Short Way to Corn, 1984 Mar (Box 217, Folder 48)
      - Continuity, 1984 Apr (Box 217, Folder 49)
      - Singapore's Patrimony (and Matrimony), 1984 May (Box 217, Folder 50)
      - Adam's Navel, 1984 Jun (Box 217, Folder 51)
      - Carrie Buck's Daughter, 1984 Jul (Box 217, Folder 52)
      - The Cosmic Dance of Siva, 1984 Aug (Box 217, Folder 53)
      - Only His Wings Remained, 1984 Sep (Box 217, Folder 54)
      - The Rule of Five, 1984 Oct (Box 217, Folder 55)
      - Human Equality Is a Contingent Fact of History, 1984 Nov (Box 217, Folder 56)
      - A Most Ingenious Paradox, 1984 Dec (Box 217, Folder 57)
      - The Sinister and the Trivial, 1985 Jan (Box 217, Folder 58)
      - Nasty Little Facts, 1985 Feb (Box 217, Folder 59)
      - The Flamingo's Smile, 1985 Mar (Box 217, Folder 60)
      - A Clock of Evolution, 1985 Apr (Box 217, Folder 61)
      - Red Wings in the Sunset, 1985 May (Box 217, Folder 62)
      - Fleeming Jenkin Revisited, 1985 Jun (Box 217, Folder 63)
      - Here Goes Nothing, 1985 Jul (Box 217, Folder 64)
      - To Be a Platypus, 1985 Aug (Box 217, Folder 65)
      - Bligh's Bounty, 1985 Sep (Box 217, Folder 66)
      - Not Necessarily a Wing, 1985 Oct (Box 217, Folder 67)
      - Geoffroy and the Homeobox, 1985 Nov (Box 218, Folder 1)
      - Geoffroy and the Homeobox, 1985 Nov (Box 452, Folder 1)
      - Treasures in a Taxonomic Wastebasket, 1985 Dec (Box 218, Folder 2)
      - A Short Way to Big Ends, 1986 Jan (Box 218, Folder 3)
      - Play it Again, Life, 1986 Feb (Box 218, Folder 4)
      - On Rereading Edmund Halley, 1986 Mar (Box 218, Folder 5)
      - Glow, Big Glowworm, 1986 Dec (Box 218, Folder 6)
      - Soapy Sam's Logic, 1986 Apr (Box 218, Folder 7)
      - Knight Takes Bishop?, 1986 May (Box 218, Folder 8)
      - Fortitude From Heaven, 1986 Jun (Box 218, Folder 9)
      - The Egg-a-Day Barrier, 1986 Jul (Box 218, Folder 10)
      - Linnaean Limits, 1986 Aug (Box 218, Folder 11)
      - The Archaeopteryx Flap, 1986 Sep (Box 218, Folder 12)
      - Archetype and Adaptation, 1986 Oct (Box 218, Folder 13)
      - Of Kiwi Eggs and the Liberty Bell, 1986 Nov (Box 218, Folder 14)
      - The Panda's Thumb of Technology, 1987 Jan (Box 218, Folder 15)
      - Freudian Slip, 1987 Feb (Box 218, Folder 16)
      - Hatracks and Theories, 1987 Mar (Box 218, Folder 17)
      - Life's Little Joke, 1987 Apr (Box 218, Folder 18)
      - Empire of the Apes, 1987 May (Box 218, Folder 19)
      - Empire of the Apes, 1987 May (Box 218, Folder 20)
      - Bushes All the Way Down, 1987 Jun (Box 218, Folder 21)
      - Petrus Camper's Angle, 1987 Jul (Box 218, Folder 22)
      - An Universal Freckle, 1987 Aug (Box 218, Folder 23)
      - The Godfather of Disaster, 1987 Sep (Box 218, Folder 24)
      - Justice Scalia's Misunderstanding, 1987 Oct (Box 218, Folder 25)
      - William Jennings Bryan's Last Campaign, 1987 Nov (Box 218, Folder 26)
      - Freud's Phylogenetic Fantasy, 1987 Dec (Box 218, Folder 27)
      - The Case of the Creeping Fox Terrier Clone, 1988 Jan (Box 218, Folder 28)
      - The Heart of Terminology, 1988 Feb (Box 218, Folder 29)
      - Honorable Men and Women, 1988 Mar (Box 218, Folder 30)
      - Pretty Pebbles, 1988 Apr (Box 218, Folder 31)
      - A Tale of Three Pictures, 1988 May (Box 218, Folder 32)
      - A Novel Notion of Neanderthal, 1988 Jun (Box 218, Folder 33)
      - Kropotkin Was No Crackpot, 1988 Jul (Box 218, Folder 34)
      - In a Jumbled Drawer, 1988 Aug (Box 218, Folder 35)
      - Genesis and Geology, 1988 Sep (Box 218, Folder 36)
      - A Web of Tales, 1988 Oct (Box 218, Folder 37)
      - The Ant and the Plant, 1988 Nov (Box 218, Folder 38)
      - Ten Thousand Acts of Kindness, 1988 Dec (Box 218, Folder 39)
      - An Essay on a Pig Roast, 1989 Jan (Box 218, Folder 40)
      - Grimm's Greatest Tale, 1989 Feb (Box 218, Folder 41)
      - The Wheel of Fortune and the Wedge of Progress, 1989 Mar (Box 218, Folder 42)
      - Tires to Sandals, 1989 Apr (Box 218, Folder 43)
      - George Canning's Left Buttock and the Origin of Species, 1989 May (Box 218, Folder 44)
      - The Passion of Antoine Lavoisier, 1989 Jun (Box 218, Folder 45)
      - The Chain of Reason vs. the Chain of Thumbs, 1989 Jul (Box 218, Folder 46)
      - The Dinosaur Rip-off, 1989 Aug (Box 218, Folder 47)
      - Through a Lens, Darkly, 1989 Sep (Box 218, Folder 48)
      - Full of Hot Air, 1989 Oct (Box 218, Folder 49)
      - The Creation Myths of Cooperstown, 1989 Nov (Box 218, Folder 50)
      - The Horn of Triton, 1989 Dec (Box 218, Folder 51)
      - Counters and Cable Cars, 1990 Jan (Box 218, Folder 52)
      - Bully for Brontosaurus, 1990 Feb (Box 218, Folder 53)
      - An Earful of Jaw, 1990 Mar (Box 218, Folder 54)
      - Men of the Thirty-third Division, 1990 Apr (Box 218, Folder 55)
      - Bent out of Shape, 1990 May (Box 218, Folder 56)
      - Everlasting Legends, 1990 Jun (Box 218, Folder 57)
      - In Touch with Walcott, 1990 Jul (Box 218, Folder 58)
      - Muller Bros. Moving & Storage, 1990 Aug (Box 218, Folder 59)
      - The Golden Rule-a Proper Scale for Our Environmental Crisis, 1990 Sep (Box 218, Folder 60)
      - Enigmas of the Small Shellies, 1990 Oct (Box 218, Folder 61)
      - The Golden Rule-a Proper Scale for Our Environmental Crisis, 1990 Sep (Box 218, Folder 60)
      - Enigmas of the Small Shellies, 1990 Oct (Box 218, Folder 61)
      - Darwin and Paley Meet the Invisible Hand, 1990 Nov (Box 219, Folder 1)
      - Shoemaker and Morning Star, 1990 Dec (Box 219, Folder 2)
      - Eight (or Fewer) Little Piggies, 1991 Jan (Box 219, Folder 3)
      - More Light on Leaves, 1991 Feb (Box 452, Folder 2)
      - More Light on Leaves, 1991 Feb (Box 219, Folder 4)
      - The Great Seal Principle, 1991 Mar (Box 219, Folder 5)
      - What the Immaculate Pigeon Teaches the Burdened Mind, 1991 Apr (Box 219, Folder 6)
      - Abolish the Recent, 1991 May (Box 219, Folder 7)
      - On the Loss of a Limpet, 1991 Jun (Box 219, Folder 8)
      - Of Mice and Mosquitoes, 1991 Jul (Box 219, Folder 9)
      - Opus 200, 1991 Aug (Box 219, Folder 10)
      - Unenchanted Evening, 1991 Sep (Box 219, Folder 11)
      - The Moral State of Tahiti--and of Darwin, 1991 Oct (Box 219, Folder 12)
      - Fall in the House of Ussher, 1991 Nov (Box 219, Folder 13)
      - The Smoking Gun of Eugenics, 1991 Dec (Box 219, Folder 14)
      - "The Reversal of Hallucigenia", 1992 Jan (Box 219, Folder 15)
      - Mozart and Modularity, 1992 Feb (Box 219, Folder 16)
      - Does the Stoneless Plum Instruct the Thinking Reed?, 1992 Apr (Box 219, Folder 17)
      - The Most Unkindest Cut of All, 1992 May (Box 219, Folder 18)
      - We Are All Monkeys' Uncles, 1992 Jun (Box 219, Folder 19)
      - A Humongous Fungus Among Us, 1992 Jul (Box 219, Folder 20)
      - Sweetness and Light, 1992 Aug (Box 219, Folder 21)
      - Magnolias from Moscow, 1992 Sep (Box 219, Folder 22)
      - Life in a Punctuation, 1992 Oct (Box 219, Folder 23)
      - Red in Tooth Claw, 1992 Nov (Box 219, Folder 24)
      - Columbus Cracks and Egg, 1992 Dec (Box 219, Folder 25)
      - A Special Fondness for Beetles, 1993 Jan (Box 219, Folder 26)
      - Cordelia's Dilemma, 1993 Feb (Box 219, Folder 27)
      - Modified Grandeur, 1993 Mar (Box 219, Folder 28)
      - The First Unmasking of Nature, 1993 Apr (Box 219, Folder 29)
      - Four Antelopes of the Apocalypse, 1993 May (Box 219, Folder 30)
      - The Invisible Woman, 1993 Jun (Box 219, Folder 31)
      - Poe's Greatest Hit, 1993 Jul (Box 219, Folder 32)
      - The Gift of New Questions, 1993 Aug (Box 219, Folder 33)
      - The Gift of New Questions, 1993 Aug (Box 452, Folder 3)
      - Fungal Forgery, 1993 Sep (Box 219, Folder 34)
      - The Razumovsky Duet, 1993 Oct (Box 219, Folder 35)
      - The Sexual Politics of Classification, 1993 Nov (Box 219, Folder 36)
      - Four Metaphors in Three Generations, 1993 Dec (Box 219, Folder 37)
      - Cabinet Museums Revisited, 1994 Jan (Box 220, Folder 1)
      - In the Mind of the Beholder, 1994 Feb (Box 220, Folder 2)
      - In the Mind of the Beholder, 1994 Feb (Box 452, Folder 11)
      - The Persistently Flat Earth, 1994 Mar (Box 220, Folder 3)
      - Dousing Diminutive Dennis's Debate, 1994 Apr (Box 220, Folder 4)
      - Hooking Leviathan by Its Past, 1994 May (Box 220, Folder 5)
      - The Power of This View of Life, 1994 Jun (Box 220, Folder 6)
      - The Monster's Human Nature, 1994 Jul (Box 220, Folder 7)
      - Happy Thoughts on a Sunny Day in New York City, 1994 Aug (Box 220, Folder 8)
      - Happy Thoughts on a Sunny Day in New York City, 1994 Aug (Box 452, Folder 4)
      - Lucy on the Earth in Stasis, 1994 Sep (Box 220, Folder 9)
      - Jove's Thunderbolts, 1994 Oct (Box 220, Folder 10)
      - The Celestial Mechanic and the Earthly Naturalist, 1994 Nov (Box 220, Folder 11)
      - Common Pathways of Illumination, 1994 Dec (Box 220, Folder 12)
      - Common Pathways of Illumination, 1994 Dec (Box 452, Folder 5)
      - Of Tongue Worms, Velvet Worms, and Water Bears, 1995 Jan (Box 220, Folder 13)
      - Ghosts of Bell Curves Past, 1995 Feb (Box 220, Folder 14)
      - Evolution by Walking, 1995 Mar (Box 220, Folder 15)
      - Left Snails and Right Mind, 1995 Apr (Box 220, Folder 16)
      - Speaking of Snails and Scales, 1995 May (Box 220, Folder 17)
      - Speaking of Snails and Scales, 1995 May (Box 452, Folder 6)
      - Age-Old Fallacies of Thinking and Stinking, 1995 Jun (Box 220, Folder 18)
      - Age-Old Fallacies of Thinking and Stinking, 1995 Jun (Box 452, Folder 7)
      - Spin Doctoring Darwin, 1995 Jul (Box 220, Folder 19)
      - Spin Doctoring Darwin, 1995 Jul (Box 452, Folder 8)
      - Boyle's Law and Darwin's Details, 1995 Aug (Box 220, Folder 20)
      - Boyle's Law and Darwin's Details, 1995 Aug (Box 452, Folder 9)
      - Reversing Established Orders, 1995 Sep (Box 220, Folder 21)
      - "The Great Western and The Fighting Temeraire", 1995 Oct (Box 220, Folder 22)
      - A Sea Horse for All Races, 1995 Nov (Box 220, Folder 23)
      - The Anatomy Lesson, 1995 Dec (Box 220, Folder 24)
      - The Anatomy Lesson, 1995 Dec (Box 452, Folder 10)
      - Triumph of the Root-Heads, 1996 Jan (Box 220, Folder 25)
      - On a Toothed Bird's Place in Nature, 1996 Feb (Box 220, Folder 26)
      - Microcosm, 1996 Mar (Box 220, Folder 27)
      - Can We Truly Know Sloth and Rapacity?, 1996 Apr (Box 221, Folder 1)
      - Can We Truly Know Sloth and Rapacity?, 1996 Apr (Box 452, Folder 12)
      - The Tallest Tale, 1996 May (Box 221, Folder 2)
      - The Tallest Tale, annotated, 1996 May (Box 560, Folder 1)
      - Mr. Sophia's Pony, 1996 Jun (Box 221, Folder 3)
      - Up Against a Wall, 1996 Jul (Box 221, Folder 4)
      - A Lesson from the Old Masters, 1996 Aug (Box 221, Folder 5)
      - The Diet of Worms and the Defenestration of Prague, 1996 Sep (Box 221, Folder 6)
      - The Diet of Worms and the Defenestration of Prague, 1996 Sep (Box 923, Folder 10)
      - "A Cerion for Christopher", 1996 Oct (Box 221, Folder 7)
      - The Dodo in the Caucus Race, 1996 Nov (Box 923, Folder 9)
      - The Dodo in the Caucus Race, 1996 Nov (Box 221, Folder 8)
      - War of the Worldviews, 1996 Dec-1997 Jan (Box 221, Folder 9)
      - As the Worm Turns, 1997 Feb (Box 221, Folder 10)
      - Nonoverlapping Magisteria, 1997 Mar (Box 221, Folder 11)
      - Unusual Unity, 1997 Apr (Box 221, Folder 12)
      - Leonardo's Living Earth, 1997 May (Box 221, Folder 13)
      - Dolly's Fashion and Louis's Passion, 1997 Jun (Box 221, Folder 14)
      - Seeing Eye to Eye, 1997 Jul-Aug (Box 221, Folder 15)
      - Drink Deep, or Taste Not the Pierian Spring, 1997 Sep (Box 221, Folder 16)
      - A Tale of Two Worksites, 1997 Oct (Box 221, Folder 17)
      - Room of One's Own, 1997 Nov (Box 221, Folder 18)
      - The Paradox of the Visibly Irrelevant, 1997 Dec-1998 Jan (Box 221, Folder 19)
      - An Awful, Terrible Dinosaurian Irony, 1998 February (Box 221, Folder 20)
      - The Internal Brand of the Scarlet, 1998 Mar (Box 221, Folder 21)
      - The Lying Stones of Wurzburg and Marrakech, 1998 Apr (Box 221, Folder 22)
      - The Sharp-Eyed Lynx Outfoxed by Nature, 1998 May (Box 221, Folder 23)
      - The Sharp-Eyed Lynx Outfoxed by Nature, Part Two, 1998 Jun (Box 221, Folder 24)